Guide to the James Marshall Osborn Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James Marshall Osborn correspondence
1928-1977
OSB MSS 7
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
32.25
(81 boxes)
The correspondence concerns the scholarly and collecting interests of James Marshall Osborn. The collection documents his activities as a rare book and manuscript collector, his research in early modern and eighteenth century English literature, and his authorship of several volumes of literary history. Much of the correspondence is with other literary scholars, including F. W. Bateson, James Lowry Clifford, Wilmarth S. Lewis, Maynard Mack. Chauncey Brewster Tinker, and René Wellek.
Osborn, James M. (James Marshall), 1906-1976
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of James Marshall Osborn.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
JAMES MARSHALL OSBORN (1906-1976)
James Marshall Osborn, literary historian, founder of the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection at Yale University, and Holstein cattle breeder, was born in Cleveland, Ohio in 1906. He graduated from Wesleyan University in 1928, and joined the investment advisory department of Guaranty Trust in New York. The next year, he married Marie-Louise Montgomery, a graduate of Vassar.
In 1932 Osborn left Guaranty Trust to study for a Master's degree in English at Columbia University. Two years later, the Osborns moved to England with their two sons, and James began to work toward a B.Litt degree at Oxford University. While at Oxford, Osborn pursued his interest in eighteenth-century literary history and began to acquire the literary and historical manuscripts that would form the core of the Osborn Collection.
Osborn was appointed Research Associate in English at Yale University in 1938; he held the position until the time of his death. He was named Adviser on Seventeenth Century Manuscripts to the Yale Library in 1954, and in 1963, when he began the transfer of his collection to Yale, became the first curator of the Osborn Collection.
Osborn's publications include The Autobiography of Thomas Whythorne (1961); an edition of Joseph Spence's Observations, Anecdotes and Characters (1966); and Young Philip Sidney (1972).
In addition to his scholarly activities, Osborn was also a noted dairy cattle breeder and promoter of Holsteins from 1940 to 1960. He received the D.Litt from Oxford University in 1968, and was named Curator Emeritus of the Osborn Collection in 1972. James Marshall Osborn died in New Haven on October 17, 1976.
Scope and Contents
The correspondence concerns the scholarly and collecting interests of James Marshall Osborn. The collection documents his activities as a rare book and manuscript collector, his research in early modern and eighteenth century English literature, and his authorship of several volumes of literary history. Much of the correspondence is with other literary scholars, including F. W. Bateson, James Lowry Clifford, Wilmarth S. Lewis, Maynard Mack, Chauncey Brewster Tinker, and René Wellek.
Book collecting -- United States; English literature -- 18th century -- History and criticism; English literature -- Early modern, 1500-1700 -- History and criticism; Learning and scholarship -- United States -- History -- 20th Century; Scholars -- United States; Universities and colleges -- Study and teaching -- United States; Balderston, Katharine Canby, 1895-; Bateson, Frederick Wilse, 1901-1978; Bentley, Harold W., 1899-1980; Bowers, Fredson, 1905-1991; Boys, Richard C. (Richard Charles), 1912-1975; Brooks, Cleanth, 1906-1994; Chapman, R. W. (Robert William), 1881-1960; Chapple, J. A. V., 1928-; Clifford, James L. (James Lowry), 1901-1978; Copeland, Thomas Wellsted, 1907-; Crane, Ronald S. (Ronald Salmon), 1886-1967; Croft, P. J. (Peter John), 1929-1984; Davin, Dan, 1913-1990; De Beer, Esmond Samuel, 1895-1990; Dobell, Percy John, 1871-1956; Eccles, Mary Hyde, 1912-; Gardner, Helen, 1908-1986; Greene, Richard Leighton; Greg, W. W. (Walter Wilson), 1875-1959; Halsband, Robert, 1914-1989; Hemlow, Joyce; Hilles, Frederick W. (Frederick Whiley), 1900-1975; Klima, Slava; Lewis, W. S. (Wilmarth Sheldon), 1895-1979; Mack, Maynard, 1909-2001; Malone, Edmond, 1741-1812 -- Criticism and interpretation; Manwaring, Elizabeth Wheeler, 1879-; McManaway, James Gilmer, 1899-1980; Metzdorf, Robert F. (Robert Frederic), 1912-; Parks, Stephen, 1940-; Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-1975; Powell, Lawrence Fitzroy, 1881-1975; Sherburn, George, 1884-1962; Sutherland, James Runcieman, 1900-1996; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; Vieth, David M.; Waith, Eugene M., 1912-; Wellek, René, 1903-1995; Wimsatt, William K. (William Kurtz), 1907-1975; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- History; Yale University. Library
- Box and Folder List, 1960
  - Abbott, C. Colleer, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Spence queries
  - Abbott, John L., 1966-75 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Hawkesworth scholar, University of Connecticut
  - Abbott, W. C., 1954 Jun 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Cromwell scholar, Harvard
  - Abrams, Meyer, 1958-75 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Department of English, Cornell
  - Achtert, Walter S., 1969-76 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    MLA
  - Adam, Donald G., 1963-65 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Department of English, Bowdoin College
  - Adams, Charles Kingsley, 1899-1971, 1940-75 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    Director, National Portrait Gallery
  - Adams, Charles M., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Assistant to Director of Libraries, Columbia University
  - Adams, Frederick B., Jr., 1939-67 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Director, Pierpont Morgan Library, Johnsonian
  - Adams, H. M., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Librarian, Trinity College, Cambridge
  - Adams, Henry H., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adams, Joseph Q., 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Director, Folger Shakespeare Library
  - Adams, Robert M., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Adams, Thomas R., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Librarian, John Carter Brown Library
  - Ahmed, M. S., 1967-71 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Graduate student, Hull
  - Alden, John, 1952-68 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Librarian, Riggs Memorial Library Georgetown University
  - Aldrich, Richard Stoddard, Sr. and Jr., 1935-70 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alexander, Peter, 1954-57 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Review of English Studies, Glasgow University
  - Allan, David G. C., 1961-76 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Allen, C. K., 1935-64 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Warden, Rhodes House, Oxford
  - Allen, Don Cameron, 1946-61 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Department of English, Johns Hopkins
  - Allen, Edw. G. & Son, Ltd., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    London booksellers
  - Allen, H. C., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Department of History, University of Virginia
  - Allen, Robert J., 1953-72 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Department of English, Williams College
  - Allentuck, Marcia, 1965-71 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Alleyne, S. M., 1955-56 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Owner of Burney MSS
  - Altenbernd, Lynn, 1955-56 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Department of English, University of Illinois
  - Altick, Richard D., 1941-49 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Department of English, Ohio State University
  - Amberg, Anthony, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Graduate student, University of Chicago, Edward Moore
  - Ameen, Dr. Lane, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Purchaser of J. M. Osborn's house, 77 Edgehill Road
  - Anderson, George L., 1952-54 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Department of English, University of Maryland, Egerton MS
  - Angell, Joseph, 1974-75 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Department of English, Colorado State University
  - Antiquarian Book Shop (Dorking) Ltd., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Archer, H. Richard, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Editor, Augustan Reprint Society
  - Aris, Joyce M., 1961-62 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Copied Wesley portrait in NPG for J. M. Osborn to give to Wesleyan
  - Arms, George, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Department of English, University of New Mexico
  - Armytage, Walter, 1971-75 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Malone
  - Arnold, Robert H., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Wesleyan friend
  - Aronson, Steven M. L., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Oxford friend
  - Ashbrook, Elizabeth, (Egerton Warburton), Viscountess, 1937-38 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Dryden MS
  - Ashby, Arthur W., 1951-52 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    J. P. Collier scholar, Exeter College, Oxford
  - Aspinall, A., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Department of History, Reading, Fox MSS
  - The Athenaeum, 1968-73 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Atkinson, R. L., 1953-54 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Secretary, Historical MSS Commission
  - Austen-Leigh, R. A., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    President, Bibliographical Society
  - Austin, Gabriel, 1963-69 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Librarian, Grolier Club
  - Austin, John Denham, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Denham scholar
  - Averill, Heman B., 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    City administration
  - Avery, Emmett L., 1951-65 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    State College of Washington
  - Babb, James T., 1940-64 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    Librarian, Yale University Library
  - Babcock, R. W., 1938 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    University of Michigan, 18th century Shakespeare criticism
  - Bachrach, Fabian and Bradford, 1954-60 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Photographers
  - Baer, Richard A., Jr. and Joan (Riddell), 1962-69 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    Relatives
  - Bakeless, John, 1939-65 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    Retired professor from New York University, friend
  - Baker, Dame Janet, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 56)
    Singer
  - Baker, Herschel, 1947-66 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    Department of English, Harvard, 17th century
  - Baker, J. R., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    Bookseller
  - Bald, R. C., 1939-51 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Balderston, Katharine C., 1940-64 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    Department of English, Wellesley College, editor of Thraliana
  - Ballantine, Edward and Florence, 1937-69 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Banks, J. Richard, 1954-63 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    Yale News Bureau
  - Banks, Theodore, 1958-68 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    Department of English, Wesleyan
  - Barber, Giles, 1966-75 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    The Taylorian Institution, Oxford
  - Barker, Conway, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Barker, Nicholas, 1967-72 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    Editor, The Book Collector
  - Barlow, Basil S., 1962-76 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    Johnsonian
  - Barnard, John, 1961-75 (Box 3, Folder 68-73)
    J. M. Osborn's research assistant, 1961-64, Department of English, University of Leeds
  - Barnes, Chaplin Bradford, 1964-65 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    Yale College and Law School, University College, Oxford
  - Barrett, Oliver R., 1937-41 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    Collector (Dryden)
  - Bartholomew, Marshall, 1946-49 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    Director, Yale Glee Club
  - Bartlett, Henrietta, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    Shakespeare scholar
  - Bate, Walter Jackson, 1918-, 1956-76 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    Department of English, Harvard, Johnson scholar
  - Bates, Robert C., 1968-69 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    Association of American Rhodes Scholars
  - Bateson, Frederick Wilse, 1901-, 1935-47 (Box 4, Folder 80-89)
    Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature, old, close Oxford friend
  - Battestin, Martin, 1960-71 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Beals, John D., Jr., 1935-71 (Box 5, Folder 91-95)
    Lawyer, New York
  - Batty, W. Rayner, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Beard, Geoffrey, 1952-74 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    18th century scholar
  - Beattie, William, 1965-74 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    National Library of Scotland, Edinburgh
  - Beaurline, Lester A., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    University of Virginia, Beaumont and Fletcher
  - Beddall, Thomas H., Jr., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    New Haven Symphony Orchestra
  - Behrens, Edith, 1954-60 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    Musical friend
  - Beinecke, Edwin J., Jr. and Frederick W. (Box 5, Folder 102)
    Collectors and donors
  - Belanger, Terry, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    Bibliographer
  - Belgion, Helen, 1970-74 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    Dryden
  - Bell, Alan Scott, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    National Library of Scotland
  - Bell, Herbert C. F., 1936-39 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    Professor (Oxford ?)
  - Bell, John, 1961-76 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    Oxford University Press
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Oxford University Press, Box 9, folder 193.
  - Bell, Robert E., 1973 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    McGill University
  - Benedick's Song in Much Ado About Nothing, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Benjamin, Walter R., 1949-66 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Benkovitz, Miriam, 1955-57 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    Skidmore College, Burney Family
  - Bennett, Charles H., 1942-55 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    Boswell and Walpole editions
  - Bennett, E. K., 1945 Feb 11 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    Gonville and Caius, Cambridge
  - Bennett, H. Stanley, 1959-68 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    Folger Library, Emmanuel College, Cambridge
  - Benson, Adolph B., 1957 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    Dryden, Wesleyan
  - Bentley, G. E., Sr. and Jr., 1954-76 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    Father and son, both scholars, Princeton and Chicago-Toronto
  - Bentley, Harold W., 1939-76 (Box 6, Folder 117-122)
    Index Society, MLA
  - Benton, Thomas Hart and Rita, 1959-70 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    Artist and friend
  - Bergin, Thomas, 1958-69 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    Elizabethan Club, etc.
  - Bernbaum, Ernest, 1940-41 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    Department of English, University of Illinois, MLA, etc.
  - Besterman, Theodore, 1955-69 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    Voltaire
  - Betjeman, Sir John, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 127)
    Malone mausoleum
  - Bevis, Palmer L., 1950-53 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    Lawyer
  - Bill, E. G. W., 1956-67 (Box 7, Folder 129)
    Librarian, Lambeth Palace
  - Billington, Ray A., 1972-73 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    Huntington Library
  - Bingle, R. J., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 131)
    Ozias Humphrey
  - Bird, Alice H., 1954 (Box 7, Folder 132)
    Shakespeare
  - Bissonette, T. H., 1944 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    Cattle
  - Black, Matthew W., 1939-55 (Box 7, Folder 134)
    Department of English, University of Pennsylvania
  - Black, Robert K., 1955-71 (Box 7, Folder 135-137)
  - Blackwell's, 1939-69 (Box 7, Folder 138-139)
  - Blair, Walter, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    Department of English, University of Chicago
  - Blake, Robert, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    Queen's College, Oxford
  - Blake, Whitney, 1970-71 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    Yale University Press
  - Blakeney, T. S., 1955-69 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    Friends of the National Libraries
  - Blanchard, Rae, 1943-58 (Box 7, Folder 144)
    Goucher College, Steele
  - Blankenagel, John, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    Wesleyan
  - Blanshard, Frances, 1953-56 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    Wordsworth portrait
  - Blayney, Peter W. M., 1975 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Blitzer, Charles, 1960-61 (Box 7, Folder 148)
    Yale political scientist
  - Bloom, Edward A., 1954-75 (Box 7, Folder 149)
    Brown University, Fanny Burney
  - Bloomfield, Ben, 1951-59 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Bloss, Meredith, 1958-76 (Box 7, Folder 151)
    Librarian, New Haven Free Public Library
  - Blotner, Joseph, 1962-63 (Box 7, Folder 152)
    University of Virginia, Joyce Cary
  - Blum, Albert J., 1940-67 (Box 7, Folder 153-155)
  - Blum, John, 1966-68 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    Yale Library
  - Blunden, Edmund, 1969 Nov 11 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    Friend of William Force Stead
  - Boatwright, Helen, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 158)
  - Bockel, George B., 1957-69 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    Father of Joyce Osborn (daughter-in -law; Mrs. Thomas M. Osborn)
  - Bodine, John W. (and Thomas R.), 1935-75 (Box 8, Folder 160-161)
    Lawyer, Oxford friend
  - Bodleian Library, 1937-75 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Bohan, Anne, 1968-70 (Box 8, Folder 163)
    J. M. Osborn's cook
  - Bond, Donald F., 1950-74 (Box 8, Folder 164)
    University of Chicago
  - Bond, Maurice F., 1956-62 (Box 8, Folder 165)
    House of Lord's record office
  - Bond, Richard P., 1938-73 (Box 8, Folder 166)
    University of North Carolina
  - Bond, William H., 1957-74 (Box 8, Folder 167)
    Librarian, Houghton Library, Harvard
  - Boorsch, Jean and Suzanne, 1963-68 (Box 8, Folder 168)
    Yale
  - Borchardt, Ruth, 1942-49 (Box 8, Folder 169)
    J. S. Mill, London School of Economics
  - Boswell Edition, 1965-76 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - Bowden, Mary Ellen, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 171)
    Judicial astrology in Tudor England
  - Bowditch, Anna, 1969 Jul 22 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    Headmistress, Day Prospect Hill School
  - Bowers, Fredson, 1941-72 (Box 8, Folder 173)
    University of Virginia, bibliographer
  - Boyce, Benjamin, 1960-67 (Box 8, Folder 174)
    Duke University, Ralph Allen
  - Boyd, William J. D., 1965-67 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    National Municipal League
  - Boyle, Sir Edward Charles Gurney, 3d Bart., 1923-, 1968-76 (Box 8, Folder 176)
    Malone and The Club
  - Boys, Floyd, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    University of Virginia Hospital, Department of Surgery, experimental surgery unit, head
  - Boys, Richard, 1938-60 (Box 8, Folder 178-179)
  - Bradbrook, Muriel, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 180)
  - Bradham, Jo Allen, 1959-60 (Box 9, Folder 181)
    Graduate student, Vanderbilt; Spence
  - Bradley, David, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 182)
    Monash University, Australia
  - Bradley, Lyman R., 1939-50 (Box 9, Folder 183)
  - Bradley, Morton C., 1965-67 (Box 9, Folder 184)
    Restoration of prior portrait
  - Bradner, Leicester, 1941-62 (Box 9, Folder 185)
    Brown University, Annual Bibliography
  - Brady, Frank, 1956-72 (Box 9, Folder 186)
    Boswell
  - Brainerd, Winthrop, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 187)
    Metropolitan Club
  - Branch, Anna Hempstead, 1934-35 (Box 9, Folder 188)
    Connecticut College
  - Brayne, Thomas Adrian Verney-Cave, 7th Baron, 1902-, 1955-56 (Box 9, Folder 189)
    Stanford MSS
  - Bredvold, Louis I., 1938-72 (Box 9, Folder 190)
    University of Michigan
  - Breslauer, Martin, 1962-66 (Box 9, Folder 191)
  - Brett-Smith, H. F. B., 1937-39 (Box 9, Folder 192)
  - Brett-Smith, John R. B., 1957-71 (Box 9, Folder 193)
  - Brewster, Joyce, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 194)
    Transportation of Traherne MS
  - Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1964-73 (Box 9, Folder 195)
    President of Yale
  - Brick Row Bookshop, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 196)
  - Brieff, Frank, 1967-68 (Box 9, Folder 197)
    New Haven Symphony Orchestra, music director
  - Brinkley, Florence, 1941-42 (Box 9, Folder 198)
    Goucher College
  - Brissenden, Robert F., 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 199)
    David Nichol Smith Memorial Seminar, Australia
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1954-76 (Box 9, Folder 200)
    Talk on MS hunting
  - British Museum, 1938-70 (Box 9, Folder 201)
  - British Studies, Conference on, 1960-67 (Box 9, Folder 202)
  - Brofsky, Howard, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 203)
    Burney and Martini
  - Brogan, Denis W., 1962 (Box 9, Folder 204)
    Yale Law School
  - Brodhead, Richard Chaplain, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 205)
    Yale undergraduate
  - Bronson, Bertrand, 1940-71 (Box 9, Folder 206)
    J. M. Osborn's review of Ritson biography
  - Brook, V. J. K., 1940-69 (Box 9, Folder 207)
    Oxford
  - Brooke, John, 1972-75 (Box 9, Folder 208)
    Townshend
  - Brooke, Tucker, 1939-48 (Box 9, Folder 209)
    Department of English, Yale
  - Brooker, T. Kimball, 1974 Mar 21 (Box 9, Folder 210)
    Yale Library Associates
  - Brooks, Cleanth, 1906-1994, 1940-76 (Box 9, Folder 211)
    Percy, Malone
  - Brooks, Harold F., 1940 Jul 12 (Box 9, Folder 212)
    Oldham
  - Brower, Reuben A., 1952-62 (Box 10, Folder 213)
    Harvard
  - Brown, Alan Willard, 1934-69 (Box 10, Folder 214-215)
    Columbia, Hobart-William Smith
  - Brown, Anthony, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 216)
  - Brown, David D., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 217)
  - Brown, Frank R., 1937-49 (Box 10, Folder 218)
  - Brown, John L., 1960-62 (Box 10, Folder 219)
  - Brown, Sylvia, 1942-44 (Box 10, Folder 220)
    Secretary, Connecticut War Council
  - Browne-Swinburne, Joan, 1962-63 (Box 10, Folder 221)
    Blount sisters
  - Brownell, Morris R., 1964-65 (Box 10, Folder 222)
    Pope
  - Brownell, Samuel M., 1957-74 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    Yale, education
  - Bryant, Donald C., 1941 (Box 10, Folder 224)
    Burke
  - Bryce, J. C., 1936-66 (Box 10, Folder 225)
  - Bryson, John, 1960 Mar 23 (Box 10, Folder 226)
    Balliol, Oxford (Roger Lonsdale)
  - Buffum, Imbrie, 1956-73 (Box 10, Folder 227)
    Yale, Silliman, etc.
  - Buhler, Curt, 1950-68 (Box 10, Folder 228)
    Pierpont Morgan Library
  - Bullock, Sir Alan, 1960-75 (Box 10, Folder 229)
    St. Catherine's, Oxford
  - Burgess, Charles F., 1962-70 (Box 10, Folder 230)
    Virginia Military Institute
  - Burney, Albert Bernard, ca. 1871-1950, 1948-50 (Box 10, Folder 231)
    Descendent of Dr. Burney, Malone collector
  - Burney-Cumming, James C., 1953-54 (Box 10, Folder 232)
    Descendent of Dr. Burney
  - Burnim, Kalman A., 1975 (Box 10, Folder 233)
    Dr. Burney
  - Bush, Douglas, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 234)
  - Bush, Prescott, Senator, 1954-63 (Box 10, Folder 235)
    Clubs
  - Butler, Belinda Norman, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 236)
    Sidney
  - Butt, John Everett, 1906-1965, and Enid Margaret (Hope), 1935-67 (Box 10, Folder 237)
  - Butterfield, Victor M., 1941-65 (Box 10, Folder 238)
    President, Wesleyan
  - Buxton, John, 1966-75 (Box 10, Folder 239)
    Oxford, Sidney
  - Cahill, Joseph T. (St. John's University), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 240)
    Honorary degree
  - Cahoon, Herbert, 1962-64 (Box 11, Folder 241)
    Morgan Library, Malone
  - Calleo, David, 1960-68 (Box 11, Folder 242)
    Manuscript Society
  - Cameron, William, 1954-75 (Box 11, Folder 243)
    POAS
  - Camp, Anthony J., 1967 (Box 11, Folder 244)
    Society of Genealogists
  - Canfield, Curtis, 1962-69 (Box 11, Folder 245)
    Yale Drama School
  - Canfield, J. Douglas, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 246)
    UCLA
  - Cannon, Beekman C. and Margaret, 1957-75 (Box 11, Folder 247)
    Yale music, New Haven Symphony Orchestra
  - Cannon, Garland, 1965-75 (Box 11, Folder 248)
    Sir William Jones
  - Cargill, Oscar, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 249)
    New York University, Dryden
  - Carlebach, Julius, 1955-58 (Box 11, Folder 250)
    Gallery, New York (Linton Collection of African sculpture, etc.)
  - Carlson, C. Lennert, 1939-40 (Box 11, Folder 251)
    Colby College
  - Carnegie Book Shop, 1950-67 (Box 11, Folder 252)
  - Carpenter, Nan, 1962-73 (Box 11, Folder 253)
    Whythorne
  - Carroll, Roy and Charlotte, 1948-58 (Box 11, Folder 254)
    Old family friends
  - Carter, John, 1938-71 (Box 11, Folder 255)
    Sotheby's, bibliographer
  - Carter, Mark, 1953-56 (Box 11, Folder 256)
  - Case, Arthur, 1937-52 (Box 11, Folder 257)
    Northwestern, MLA, etc.
  - Caskey, J. Homer, 1939-41 (Box 11, Folder 258)
    Ohio University
  - Cassell & Co., Ltd., 1956 (Box 11, Folder 259)
  - Casella, William N., 1970-76 (Box 11, Folder 260)
  - Cecil, C. D., 1964-65 (Box 11, Folder 261)
    McGill, Burney
  - Chadwick, Henry, 1972-73 (Box 11, Folder 262)
    Dean, Christ Church, Oxford
  - Chalmers, John P., 1968-72 (Box 11, Folder 263)
    Luttrell, Librarian, Washington Cathedral
  - Chamberlin, Mac A., 1957-63 (Box 11, Folder 264)
    Wesleyan '28
  - Chambers, Robert D., 1968-69 (Box 11, Folder 265)
    Temple, Sir William
  - Champion, S. Gurney, 1937-38 (Box 11, Folder 266)
    Osborn MS of English proverbs
  - Chapman, R. W., 1935-43 (Box 11, Folder 267)
  - Chapple, John, 1955-71 (Box 12, Folder 268-270)
    J. M. Osborn's research assistant, 1955-58, University of Manchester, Hull
  - Charavey, Maison, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 271)
  - Chase, Peter Pineo, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 272)
    Johnson and Boswell
  - Chesterfield, Earl of, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 273)
    Dryden MSS
  - Chetwynd, Adam Duncan Chetwynd, 9th Viscount, 1904-1965, 1951 Dec 10 (Box 12, Folder 274)
    Dryden-Pope MSS
  - Chicago, University of, Librarianship, 1941-42 (Box 12, Folder 275)
  - Chicago Press, University of, 1951-56 (Box 12, Folder 276)
  - Chidester, Harriet, 1966-72 (Box 12, Folder 277)
    Boswell Factory
  - Childs, Richard S., 1954-71 (Box 12, Folder 278)
    City management